So the correct answer is this check here.
正确答案是这个选项
While not dice one is the same as dice two and dice two is the same as dice three.
也就是当非 dice1 等于 dice2 且 dice2 等于 dice3 时
Let's try them all one by one and see why only this one works.
我们一个个选项来试 看看为什么只有这个奏效
Let's try out this condition here.
先试试这个条件
while(dice1==dice2 || dice2==dice3).
当 dice1 等于 dice2 或 dice2 等于 dice3 时
Imagine we have this scenario where the three dice are six, three, and one.
想象这么个情景 三个骰子点数分别为 6、3 和 1
Which means dice1 is six,
也就是说 dice1 为 6
dice2 is three, and dice3 is one.
dice2 为 3 dice3 为 1
To see what this entire condition evaluates to,
要知道这整个条件会怎么判断
let's take it part by part.
我们把它拆开来看
This part here is checking if dice1 is the same as
这个部分判断的是 dice1 是否等于 dice2
dice2 and it's not, so that will be false.
这里不等于 所以条件为假
This part here checks if dice2 is the same as dice3 and it's not,
这个部分是判断 dice2 是否等于 dice3 不是
so that's also false.
所以也为假
And because those two falses are separated by an or,
因为两个假值由 or 分隔开
it evaluates the entire place to be false,
所以整个条件为假
which means we will not step into a while loop and
也就是说我们不会进入 while 循环
we will not re-roll even though this scenario should have allowed us to re-roll.
不会重掷骰子 而这个情景其实是需要重掷的
That means this condition won't work.
也就意味着这个条件不行
Okay. Let's try this condition instead,
好了 试试这个条件
dice1 is the same as dice2,
dice1 等于 dice2
and dice2 is the same as dice3.
且 dice2 等于 dice3
If we go with the same scenario again,
重复上面的情景
so dice1 is six,
也就是 dice1 为 6
dice2 is three, and dice3 is one.
dice2 为 3 dice3 为 1
This part evaluates to false and this part also evaluates to false.
这个部分会被判断为假 这个部分也会被判为假
And those two falses are separated with an and,
两个假值由 and 分隔开
which means the entire thing is also evaluated to false.
也就意味着整个条件为假
So it will not re-roll.
所以也不会重掷
And in this scenario it should have,
而这个场景就得重掷
so that also doesn't work.
所以这个条件也不行
Okay, let's try, while(dice1!= dice2 &amp;&amp; dice2!= dice3).
好了 来试试当 dice1 不等于 dice2 且 dice2 不等于 dice3 的条件
So, let's try this scenario again,
再来试试那个情景
where dice1 is six,
dice1 为 6
dice2 is three, and dice3 is one.
dice2 为 3 dice3 为 1
Now, this is checking if dice1 is not the same as dice2,
现在判断 dice1 是否不等于 dice2
and they're not the same so that evaluates to true.
不相等 所以判断结果为真
This also checks if they're not the same and three and one are not the same,
这也是要判断是否不相等 3 和 1 不相等
so that evaluates to true as well.
所以判断结果也为真
And those two trues are separated with an and,
两个真由 and 分隔开
so this entire thing evaluates to true and allows us to re-roll.
所以整个条件为真 我们可以重掷
And in that scenario, we should be re-rolling which is perfect.
而这个情景里 我们就该重掷 所以很完美
But what if the scenario was something like this?
但如果情景是这样的呢？
Where we had two threes and just one.
我们有两个 3 一个 1
In this case, dice1 would be three,
这种情况下 dice1 是 3
dice2 would also be three and dice3 would be one.
dice2 也会是 3 而 dice3 是 1
So if we have a look at this part here,
所以如果我们看这部分的话
it evaluates that dice1 and dice2 are not the same although they are,
它会判断 dice1 和 dice2 是否不相同 而它们是相同的
so that evaluates to false.
所以判断结果为假
This one checks if they're not the same and they're not the same so that's true.
这部分判断它们是否不相同 它们的确不相同 所以结果为真
But the false and true are separated by an and,
可是假与真中间由 and 连接
which means since one of them is false the whole thing becomes
也就意味着其中一个为假 整个条件都会为假
false and it doesn't step into re-roll even though it should have.
不会进入循环重掷 哪怕应该进入
So that partially works,
所以这个条件有时会奏效
but in some situations it will not allow us to re-roll when we should have.
有时虽然该重掷 却不允许我们重掷
So that doesn't work either.
所以也不行
Now finally, if we try while(!(dice1 == dice2 &amp;&amp; dice2 == dice3)){.
最后 我们来试试 当非 dice1 等于 dice2 且 dice2 等于 dice3 时这个条件
Let's try this scenario again,
还是用这个情景
three three and one.
3、3 和 1
So dice1 is three,
dice1 为 3
dice2 is also three,
dice2 也为 3
and dice3 is just one.
而 dice3 是 1
This part evaluates to true because both dice are the same.
经判断 这个部分为真 因为两个点数相同
This one evaluates to false because three and one are
这个部分为假 因为 3 和 1 不同
different and that is separated with an and,
由于两边由 and 连接
so the true and false evaluate to false.
所以一真一假判为假
But this is all surrounded with a not,
但这整个由 not 括起来了
which means that this force turns into a true.
也就意味着这个假会变为真
And in that scenario the loop would step in and re-roll.
这种情况下 循环会执行内部代码 重掷骰子
Now you could go and try all the different scenarios that you could think of.
现在你可以试试你能想到的其它情景
And every time it should step inside the while loop it will.
只要是需要进入 while 循环的情景 它都会进入
Let's have a look at a scenario where all three dice match,
我们来看看这个情景 三个骰子点数相同
which is the condition that the while should not re-roll.
这个时候 while 就不需要重掷了
In this case all dice are equal to three.
这个时候所有骰子点数都为 3
So when we start to evaluate this part evaluates to true because they're both threes.
先判断这个部分 结果为真 因为都是 3
This one also evaluates to true and two trues
然后这个部分也为真 两个真由 and 连接
separated with an and entirely evaluates to true.
所以结果为真
And that's also rounded with a not which means that this becomes false.
由于前面还有个 not 也就意味着真会变为假
Now, in this scenario we do not want to step inside
而这个情景中 我们就是不想进入循环
the loop and that's exactly what happens here with this check condition.
实际上这个判断结果也不会进入循环
So this also works.
所以这个条件可用